Lucas Coster

Looking to use my software and problem solving skills to contribute to an Engineering company working on cutting edge complex problems.

260 Main Lodge Rd Caledon, Ontario 647-290-7791 lucascoster90@gmail.com

PROJECTS

3D Model Hand — DAIR Team Member

September 2021 - April 2022

Worked on an AI model that created 3D hand meshes based on 3d images of people creating a model that was over 65% accurate. Worked with Python using Tensorflow library creating neural networks and gaining experience with auto-regressive language models. Created a paper and presented at CUCAI the Canadian University AI summit. Gained lots of experience creating Machine-Learning software.

32 Bit CPU — Course Project

January 2023 - May 2023

Built a fully working 32-bit processing unit in Quartas using the Verilog language. Fully equipped with an ALU, control unit and datapath connections. Allows assembly language instructions to be run and stored into a virtual RAM.

Ovarian Cancer Early Detection — Capstone Project

September 2023 - April 2024

Working on a full scale project with the National Cancer Institute to create a classification model which predicts how at risk a woman could be of ovarian cancer. The project runs through preprocessing, model creation and application development to create a full scale product.

EXPERIENCE

Briza, Toronto — Software Developer

May 2023 – September 2023

Developed throughout the full stack of a typescript API interface. Worked on pressing company issues, bugs and feature improvements. Gained knowledge in fast paced agile development and functional programming

QMIND, Kingston — Design Team Member

September 2021 – Present

Worked as a member of the Queens QMIND design team. Worked with Python using Tensorflow library creating neural networks and gaining experience with auto-regressive language models.

EDUCATION

Queen's University, Kingston Ontario — Fourth Year

September 2020 - Present

Enrolled in a Bachelor of Applied Science with honours, specializing in Computer Engineering, projected to graduate in 2024. Dean's Honor list in all years with a cumulative GPA above 3.5.

SKILLS

Python, TypeScript, C++, Assembly Language, HTML

Experience coding and testing AI models as well as parsing and organizing data

Knowledge of Computer Science subjects such as algorithms and object oriented programming

Experience using and developing in GIT and Agile development

Experience with software testing concepts and methodologies

Knowledge of cloud computing and coding with API's

Works well in team environments and individual environments

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Academic All-Star - 2021

Dean's Honor List - 2020 - 2023

CUUC Champions - 2023

Bronze Cross - 2019

CASI level 1 - 2017

EXTRA-CURRICULARS

Queens Varsity Athlete - Ultimate Frisbee Captain

Club Ultimate Team in Toronto

CASI Park Instructor